Brother.
My Lord Beothric.
He is mortally wounded.
Brother...
you're a king now.
Rule well...
as Father would have wished.
Eirick. Brother!
Everybody has a story to tell
about their lives.
My story begins the day I die.
There is in nature
an irregular occurrence
when the sun burns red
as the moon crosses its path.
This is the Blood Eclipse,
a time when a pathway
could be opened
between Heaven, Earth and Hel,
which the Vikings called
Valhalla, Mittgard and Helheim.
The Viking gods
used holy relics as keys
to unlock the gates
to reign over man.
But over time,
the tale faded into myth.
Men abandoned the Viking gods
and embraced the new
Christian god and his son.
Yet one god,
the God of Thunder,
did not forget.
He resolved
to take on human form,
find the keys,
and re-establish
the Viking gods
for all eternity.
Huh?
Row!
Jesus!
Norsemen!
[screaming]
Sound the alarm!
Deum de Deo,
lumen de lúmine,
Deum verum de Deo vero,
Génitum, non factum,
Consubstantiálem Patri,
- Per quem ómnia facta sunt.
- Norseman! Norseman!
The Viking Norseman!
They've come for it.
Close the door!
[yells]
Charge!
[shouts]
None enter the abbey before me.
Aye, My Lord.
God is our sword.
Faith is our shield.
Where is the abbey?
This way, My Lord.
Begone!
This is the house of God!
I am a god!
- Blasphemy!
- Silence!
I am Thor,
son of Odin,
brother of Baldur.
I've come for that
which is not yours,
nor your one god,
nor his son.
The necklace.
It is a holy relic.
Indeed.
It is the necklace
of Mary Magdalene.
You are no god.
You're blood runs
as red as a man's.
Fool.
Even Gods must travel
in the body of flesh,
here in this middle realm.
Was not your own Jesus
pierced and broken?
My Lord, we are ready
to sail with the tide.
Good.
Hmm...
I shall give you
what you truly desire,
closer thee to thy god.
[growls]
[growling]
Forgive me, old friend.
State your business.
My Lord Frey.
There's no need for that,
my friend.
Rise.
God, that stench of bear's
very strong.
Better I stink of his blood
than he of mine.
[chuckles]
Eirick Bloodletter.
High Thane of the Jomsberg.
A huntsman.
I was never fond
of that name.
Most of your kind would kill
to make such a name.
- Skal.
Eirick...
a decade in these woods,
how have you kept your wits?
I would have lost them sooner
had I stayed, My Lord.
And you managed to find
a measure of peace
up here with the bears
and the wolves?
I have.
Then my heart is heavy.
Then lighten it with
what you came here to say.
I bring you news of coming war.
Thor has returned
to the Mittgard
and gathered around him the
Northern Kings of the mortal,
the Trondelag.
There's turmoil in the world.
I was there, Eirick...
at the battle before time,
and I've seen what would
become of this world
if the Jotunn Giants
are set loose again.
I would not see
such things again.
Thor is here
to open the gates
of Valhalla,
Mittgard and Helheim.
You must stop it.
How?
I'm a man.
I am no match for a god.
But you are not just a man.
You are far more.
Ordinary men are not
brought back to life.
My sister gave you
the gift of life
because of her love of you.
For years, you lit her world
with your love.
The ultimate love.
That between a man
and a goddess.
She brought you back
because she could not bare
the world without you.
She never asked for anything
in return.
Eirick?
Freyja.
Live...
my lover.
Live.
Eirick,
you are now an undead.
Only an undead...
can pass through Helheim
and return to Mittgard.
Not even a god,
not even me,
can enter and return,
but you can.
There is in Helheim
a gilded horn.
Now, once blown
in the very face of Thor
will destroy Thor's human flesh
and send him back to the place
of spirits where he belongs.
You can choose to deny me.
You can stay here.
But the pathway will be opened
during the coming Blood Eclipse.
Retrieve the horn,
make your way
to the Henge of Stones,
inside the Fort at Trondheim.
Blow the horn there,
and Thor will be defeated.
What you ask of me
is impossible.
I would have chosen
a weaker man
had it been a simpler task.
Go first to Osberg.
There you will fine a wizard
by the name of Alcuin.
He will lead you
to the gates of Hell.
Wind to your back, Viking.
Clear skies above.
[grunting]
If you're gonna
stand there and watch,
I'd as soon you come here
and give me a hand.
I should've known it was you.
Stink of fucking bear shit
for miles.
So I'm told.
I've got to say
it's good to see you,
so bear shit be damned
'cause you're still my king,
even if you do look
like a hermit.
No longer.
I need your boat.
Well, I knew it wasn't
a courtesy call.
Look to be honest with you,
it's not mine anymore.
It belongs to another.
But I have a feeling
we could work something out.
We'll have to collect it
in Osberg.
Osberg?
That's where I'm headed
and then to Trondeheim.
Well, it's a long way,
so we best get going.
No, Sven. This journey of mine,
it's dangerous.
You have a wife,
family, child--
Yeah, and I'm a Viking
first and foremost,
so give me a moment to collect
my things and bid farewell,
and I'll be back.
You know, it's ten years.
Ten years.
I thought you would've showed
your face here before then.
[laughs]
Hey, my friend, can you
give us a ride to Osberg?
Osberg? Everyone's
going north, not east.
Kings of the Trondelag
are spending silver
like they have
a mine of it.
Wood, iron, warriors.
Anything that can go north
for war, they buy.
What business of you
in Osberg?
None of your fucking business.
Well, can you pay?
Yeah, we can pay you in fur.
If you were virgin girls,
I'd take your fur for pay.
Come on.
Give me a hand here.
[horse whinnies]
Help, help, help.
[knocking]
- Help!
- There's something inside.
Pay no attention to that.
It's just a slave.
What the--
Hah! What manner of man
is colored yellow?
Maybe he's a Laplander
or a dwarf.
Way too ugly to be an elf.
Damn you.
Enough!
Release him.
What?
You heard me. Release him.
- [chatter]
- [festive music]
That's the one.
Welcome to Osberg.
Did you think you could
mess with Ustus and live?
Now put your weapons down,
and you might live
to regret them words.
Smart tongues don't waggle
for long. Kill 'em.
You free me, I repay debt.
We're even.
It's gotta be worth
keeping the wee man.
Will you join us?
Food.
[laughing]
I'm looking for
King Karl Redbeard.
What do you want?
Tell him that Eirick Bloodletter
of the Jomsberg's here
and wishes to seek his counsel.
Alcuin the wizard.
Strange man.
I never really understood
what was in his head.
Well, he's no longer with us,
as you can see.
I'm afraid you've come
a few moons too late,
not that any of us will miss him
very much, I shouldn't think.
What happened?
A group of warriors,
Geat warriors they were,
came to trade,
not many in number.
That was the last
we saw of Alcuin.
The Geats, they've taken him
to Gotland.
Yes, Gotland.
They must've taken him
to their leader Heflar.
From what I understand,
he's not very fond of visitors,
if you know what I mean.
Anyway, if you are sincere
in finding the druid Alcuin,
then you're going to need ships.
We have a ship.
Well, then you're
going to need men.
You're going to have to cut
your way through there.
Yes, here, here.
Thank you, my dear.
A pleasure as always.
[laughs]
Well, anyway,
let me see what I can do to help
you gentlemen out this evening.
In the meantime,
let's drink, shall we?
Ahh!
By the way...
who's your friend?
We found him.
I think he might be an elf.
But he fights like a Valkyrie.
An elf, you say. Well!
A big bastard, isn't he?
Yang Fu Sun.
Yang? Is that your name?
Eirick.
Sven.
Karl.
Eirick.
- Shh-fen.
- That's close enough.
Yang.
Strange little name
for a strange wee man.
Shh-fen.
[crowd cheering]
Friends!
Kinsmen.
Thanes.
Lords.
Good fellows all, eh?
[laughs]
And the rest of you bastards.
[laughter]
Well, we have guests.
Guests of great fame
and grim repute.
Welcome Eirick Bloodletter,
once King of the Jomsbergs.
That same Eirick
who smashed the Danish army
at Jutland!
[murmuring]
Who fought outnumbered
on Zealand.
And...
back to back with his great
friend, Sven Stavanger,
fought from noon until night.
Eirick Bloodletter,
so... beloved...
of the great goddess Freyja,
that when he was
struck down in battle,
he was rised, rised, rised...
by her divine...
intervention.
Come now, brother, come.
Let us see your face, sir.
That face,
that until this night,
we have all known
only by legend.
Sir!
I stand here today
for a god has asked me
to write a song
for people to sing
in years to come.
A somber song it may be.
It requires a journey
to Helheim and back.
Yet we are Vikings
and unafraid of anything
that hell may fling on us.
So any man here who would
be a Viking, come.
Follow me.
Not exactly
an inspirational speech.
It's been a while.
You're telling me.
We're gonna be rowing
our fucking selves to Gotland.
I'm Olaf, son of Redbeard.
Welcome.
And I am Gregor,
also a Redbeard.
Welcome.
Anyone else?
Yomar.
I'm a hunter,
and my bow is yours.
Thank you.
I'm called Henrik.
Will there be any fighting?
There will, lad.
Then I'm with you.
Any chance of gold?
- [laughter]
- Not really.
Well, little enough to be
made here, I suppose.
Can you deal with
an old bugger like me?
We can.
Bernard.
Killer of women and children.
I ask again.
Any more men?
Brynna the Fair.
Daughter of Hildegard,
reader of wind.
This is not a quest for a woman.
[laughter]
Thank you, brothers.
A toast! Toast now!
To honor, to glory,
to a valiant death
and then on to
the hall of heroes. Skal!
Skal!
Please, take one of my ships.
Not this-- this bucket.
- Does it float?
- What do you care?
The man promised you
a good death,
and drowning is as good
as any other.
Olaf's right. We should
take his father's longship.
No. In this,
we'll pass unnoticed.
Hopefully leave the same way.
Sven, I told you
that woman was not to come.
- Well, I'm afraid she has to.
- Why?
You remember the conversation
we had about the boat?
Well, that is the new owner.
And captain.
You're crew on my ship.
You'll do as ordered
as any man here will.
If you don't like it,
I hope you swim well.
My Lord, we had
nothing but success.
We've raided
as far south as España,
across the Angle Sea,
and down their rivers
as far as the village of Paris.
But still no word on
the Horn of Helheim.
Whoever possesses the horn
possesses the power to stop me.
My Lord, I cannot see how.
Our warriors and our ships
are ready.
Christianity lies at our feet.
With you, a god made man,
nothing can stop us.
Even a god can be stopped.
I know you had no choice
to take me.
But I will say this wind
won't abate anytime soon.
What does a woman know
about winds and waves?
As much as anyone whose
mother died in childbirth
and whose father took her
on the longboats.
I have sailed the great seas
to Angle Isle and Greenland
and woven a course
between mountains of ice.
I've been shipwrecked
on the Great Island
and almost died of thirst,
becalmed on the Sea of Sighs.
Perhaps voyaging to Helheim
will be easier than that.
You can still get it wrong.
I say by nightfall,
we'll all be rowing.
And I say we won't.
- [whispering]
- Hmm.
We go to far Gotland,
to the Fjord of Jorgumandr.
Wolfred, get fifty men.
You!
Guard the Henge of Stones.
It has begun.
EIRICK: I can feel
the bad blood.
That's what you get
when there are strangers
sleeping next to you.
I can smell the stench
of a traitor amongst us.
Men are just so full of wind.
Eirick, Eirick.
Land ho, elf eyes.
Gotland. We're here.
This is way too quiet
for my liking.
Stay close.
[scream]
[shouting]
I got one.
Henrik!
To Helheim!
Bloodletter!
Eirick!
The broach is up there.
God, what a jail.
Prison for a wizard
of the earth.
No contact with the ground.
Are you Alcuin?
Heflar of the Geats
was many things.
None of them virtuous,
most of them cunning.
I have you to thank
for his death,
Thane of Jomsberg.
You know of me, wizard?
I saw the possibility
of your arrival.
Will you let me down?
If you promise to take me
to the gates of Helheim.
Any man may find those gates.
Most eventually do.
I plan on returning.
None who cross that bridge
may ever return,
Thane of Jomsberg.
The dead know me
as one of their own.
Ah!
Freyja's mortal lover.
I heard tell,
but did not believe.
I hear many things
from many voices,
Eirick Bloodletter.
Will you help me?
I'll show you the way.
Close it is to any man's heart
that truly seeks it.
Lower me, please.
Please.
Please let me down.
Soldiers come from the north.
Many horses.
You have powerful enemies,
Thane Eirick.
Come, wizard.
Time is against us.
A wizard was kept there, sire.
It was as you said:
an iron cage, no roof.
Good.
Now we shall see
if he's all you think he is.
Who is this wretch?
My-- My Lord...
raider ship...
killed our men,
killed our great King Heflar,
took the druid.
Who took the druid?
I heard the druid
call him by his name,
Eirick,
Thane of Jomsberg.
Heflar called him...
Bloodletter.
Eirick Bloodletter.
A fine name.
You know him, sire?
We return to Trondheim.
It is done.
My Lord, surely we should
pursue them.
No.
He will come for me.
How much further?
Oh, not far now.
In Helheim, there are many
things you must beware of,
but one thing
you cannot avoid.
At the gate of Helheim
lies a massive hound,
a hound called Garm.
He has no eyes, but he can
smell out the living
and the dead.
You may not escape.
It is there!
How do I reach it?
Swim far and deep.
Follow the current
as it gets colder and colder,
to the very depths.
There you will see the gates.
Eirick, you sure about this?
It's madness.
Aye! Madness it is.
All bravery is.
You're gonna need tallow.
Are you scared?
Terrified.
You should be.
I don't know if you're
the bravest man I've ever met
or the biggest fool.
If I don't return by sunup,
go home.
You just make sure
you come back.
Eirick go?
Eirick go.
Yang no go?
Yang no go.
Full wind with you,
my friend.
Clear skies above.
ALCUIN: Swim far and deep.
Follow the current
as it gets colder and colder,
to the very depths.
There you will see the gates.
[gasping]
[low growling]
[screaming]
Father.
Of all the torment
in this place,
none has caused me more pain
than seeing you here.
I always believed you'd stand
at the right hand of Odin.
I was a picture of a king.
A coward of worst kind.
Too afraid to live.
The door of Heaven
never opened for me.
Here I've been,
here I shall stand.
How did you know I was here?
A whisper in my ear.
This is a place for torment.
A settling of account.
Eirick, you are not my son.
Lies.
We are the dead!
Lies offer no comfort here.
Truly you're not my son.
Your mother never knew.
He came, had my face,
my image,
and she was deceived.
You are my father,
whether you seeded me or not.
Why are you here?!
I seek the Horn of Helheim.
And then?!
Then I will return.
No, my son.
You will remain here
among the dead forever.
Not without a fight.
That's the difference between
the living and the dead.
Hope.
Will you help me find it?
Hmm...
You will find the horn
within the Gate of Souls.
[moaning]
[moaning continues]
Alive.
Stay with us.
Forever.
Father, now!
[yelling]
Damn you!
[yells]
You will not have him!
Maybe we should go.
What need have we with Helheim?
He said it himself. If he
doesn't return by sunrise--
Yeah, I know what he said.
But the ship stays on course,
and so do you.
I say we leave!
Who's with me?
He's been in there
the whole night.
He's probably dead by now.
How many more of us
do you want killed?
Coward.
Where is your honor?
You're a killer of women
and children.
What do you know of honor?
All my life, I was a farmer.
But then the raiders came.
Blood of these same Geat cowards
we killed yesterday.
Burned down my farm,
my father's home,
killed my wife
and my children.
Carved me hollow,
left me blank,
so the only thing I crave
is the death I deserve.
So I killed those raiders.
I killed them all.
I killed their wives.
I killed their children.
Burned their homes
and their ships.
And I listen to their screams
as they watched their seed
wiped from the middle kingdom.
They meant to take
all that I had,
but their could not
take my honor.
And I'd rather die with honor
than to live a coward.
That's a man spoken
like a true Viking.
We wait.
Wait. Look out for Garm,
the Hound of Helheim.
He is the gatekeeper.
I past it before.
He let me through.
Just because he lets you in
doesn't mean he'll let you out.
[growling]
Run!
[growls]
We can't outrun him.
He can smell your blood.
Turn around.
Turn around, boy!
Think well me, always.
I am here!
Raahh!
Think well of me, son.
Always.
Things aren't always
as they seem, my love.
You must blow the horn
in the face of Thor to stop him.
[gasps]
[horn blowing]
Brynna, wake up.
He's there!
- Eirick.
- Brother.
- Eirick. Brother
- Eirick.
- Huh?
So you're back.
Are you gonna be all right?
Eirick, sit down
and drink this.
I saw my father.
No, you never.
What you saw was some type
of spirit made in his image.
No. It was him.
He told me I wasn't his son.
Well, that can't be true,
can it?
I grew up with you,
and I know your face,
and I know his,
and he is your father
for sure.
It makes no sense.
But you got what you went for.
You did it.
If only I knew
what she gave me
when she gave me
the gift of life,
I would've lived, Sven.
I swear I would've lived.
Yeah, but it's
not over yet, is it?
No.
So let me say something.
Something I should've said
a long, long time ago.
I've never met a man
so brave
and so afraid to be
what he actually is.
Eirick, listen to me.
You are a great man.
You were born to lead men,
to inspire men.
But ever since I've known you,
all you've ever done
is try and prove that you're
just like everybody else,
but you're not.
I am pleased to see you,
My Lord.
I doubted you would return,
and I did my best to turn aside
the crew and sail for home,
My Lord.
Warick, you seem so frightened.
Often the most cautious
are the most wise.
Warick the Wise.
There's a fine name
for a Viking.
Welcome back.
Did you decide?
What?
Am I brave or a fool?
Both.
I have to blow this horn
in the face of Thor.
Tell me what I should do.
He will be at Trondheim
at the Henge of Stones.
For the Blood Eclipse?
Yes, but you will have
the gathered armies
of the Trondelag to face.
We have an army.
It's been a very long time.
Mm.
You think your brother's
gonna be glad to see you?
No.
EIRICK: So Eirick
the Bloodletter
has became Eirick
the Harrower of Hell.
But my story is far from over.
I now have to make a journey
to the place I dread most.
Home.
With the horn and protection
of Lord Frey and Frejya,
I believe all would be well,
and the Jomsberg would
fight with me once more.
But nothing prepared me
for the biggest betrayal
that is yet to come.
Sven, drop the anchor.
Look! Jomsberg!
This doesn't feel right.
Not all of us should go.
I'll stay behind,
if it pleases you.
Perhaps you'll keep Yang.
He's a prize to men
who keep slaves.
That will be safe with me.
Yang no go?
Good.
Brynna, you stay behind.
Keep in eye on Alcuin.
State your business. This is
the fortress of Jomsberg.
We suffer no visitors.
You suffer no visitors?
What if that visitor
pulled your unconscious body
out of the Sea of Zealand?
Eirick? Is that you?
It is.
Welcome home, My Lord.
Good to see you, old friend.
Hardly a moon goes by
when our swords
don't wet the ground with
some poor bastard's claret.
We only fight for gold now.
Not like the old days.
No more rushing off
for desperate battles
with terrible odds.
No more raids.
What would your father say,
the Jomsberg, mercenaries
to the highest bidder?
I'll not be questioned by you
in this hall again, Jorgen!
If you don't like it,
then give back
your share and go!
My Lord Beothric
and great captains of Jomsberg,
I present Eirick,
son of Alfred.
Let my brother step forward.
Beothric.
- Brother.
- Eirick.
I never thought I'd see you
in this hall again.
I never thought to come.
But now that I have...
it feels good.
But I have to say
your hospitality leaves
a little bit to be desired.
You've not offered us
even a sip of water,
let alone a drop
of the hard stuff.
We drink mead in this hall
to celebrate and to mourn.
Your being here
is cause for neither.
We were warned you'd come.
Come here to take back
the throne of our father?
Brother, no.
But then,
look around you, brother.
See the poor trappings
of our father's era?
No. No, you do not.
20,000 gold coins I'm paid
by the Byzantine emperor
for a squadron
of our warriors.
Arthur of the Angles
pays me 30,000 in silver
so that I may keep
his throne safe.
For I, the younger
and lesser brother
sits on this throne,
and our kingdom is rich.
And now you come.
You're mistaken, brother.
I did not return
for the crown.
Instead I've been
asked by the gods
to take on a battle
with impossible odds.
- With whom?
- The god Thor.
Thor?
Just because he came back
from the dead,
he thinks he can take on
the God of Thunder?
I came here to ask
for your help,
not to be mocked.
Let's go.
No, brother, I cannot
allow you to leave.
A listening ear
for all who despise my reign,
a figurehead for those
who would overthrow me?
Forgive me, brother.
Take them away!
Search them and bring
whatever you find to me.
I'm sorry.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Why don't you just give
Lord Beothric what he wants?
Then we don't have to do this.
Someone's approaching,
and it's not one of us.
You are friends
of My Lord Eirick?
We are.
Then know this:
He has been betrayed.
He and his fellows
are in the dungeon.
I might get you
into the keep,
but by oath, I cannot raise
a sword against my brothers.
But you might get him out,
get him back to the boat.
Eirick needs us.
- Eirick need Yang?
- Yes.
These Jomsberg
are no brawlers, my lass.
They're the finest warriors
on earth.
Good. Arrogant men fall easiest.
We'll not pass
that courtyard unseen.
I wouldn't be so glum,
good Yorik.
Alcuin, hurry up.
Go! I will join you
in due time.
[muttering]
This leads
straight to the dungeons.
Your friends are down there.
The king is sending us north
with a slave for barter.
[chatter]
- Do you hear that?
- Shh!
Brynna! Good?
Yes, Yang, I'm fine. You?
I'm fine. Come.
- Open the gate.
- Fuck you, whore!
Open the door.
Open the door!
Whatever you say, my lady.
Hey, it's the little man.
Yang good?
No, Yang,
you're fucking brilliant.
Where's Eirick?
Next cell.
Oh...
By Odin's blind eye,
what have they done to you?
Brynna, where's the horn?
With Alcuin.
Where is he?
The druid and the horn,
where are they?
Cut them down.
I'd stay still if I were you,
My Lord.
See how he betrays
his brother?
May he not treat you the same.
What did Thor offer you
to betray me?
Why, all of the Angle Isles
to rule as I see fit.
You see, brother,
you're not the only one
with the counsel of the gods.
You can keep your Angle Isles
and the throne.
But understand this.
When I have subdued Thor,
I will come back for you,
and we will have
our reckoning.
It is you who does not
understand, brother.
The horn itself
commands the highest price.
Without it, you're worthless.
King of Jomsberg!
Would this be what you seek?
You bastard! Traitor!
My, my.
This is a fine thing.
You see, brother,
the message was very simple.
Your brother's coming,
and he carries
the Horn of Helheim.
Retrieve it and capture him.
And with the help
of your friend here, I have.
So now it's time
for my reckoning with you.
Take him away.
Treat him as befits a royal.
Use a sword.
Throw the rest of a cliff.
Druid, come.
Drink with me.
I thought there was
a traitor amongst us.
It's Alcuin the wizard.
He owes us his life.
How could he do that?
In return for Beothric's gold.
My Lord, we are with you.
We will take you away from
this place and give you shelter.
We will also gather
our group of men
to join you
to fight the Trondelag.
What about the other captains?
For them, it's treason.
That looks like it hurts.
Let me.
If this quest goes on
too much longer,
there won't be
much of you left.
We've lost the horn.
The odds are against us.
Could we not fight
without it?
The horn is the only thing
that can stop Thor.
Maybe I have no right
to ask the men to go on.
Or you.
I know you said you would ask
no more of me than any man,
but what if I wanted
to give you...
what only a woman can?
Brynna...
I promised my heart to another
many years ago.
I wondered how I ever loved
such a human fool.
Freyja?
No.
Be still there.
Don't turn around.
We are far from one another
right now,
but through this
I can speak.
I barter myself with the gods...
so that you might live again.
But your life
came with a condition,
that you and I...
can never experience
love again.
But at least you lived.
I'd rather be dead
than live my life without you.
You must.
I brought you back...
so that you should live.
We can no longer be.
Eirick...
stop living in memories.
If a man spends his life
looking backwards,
he'll miss what's
right in front of him.
And what is
right in front of me?
Hope.
A chance for joy,
happiness.
A chance for the one thing
that mortals have
that the gods desire:
love.
It's no shame to love again.
For what little time is left,
Thor has--
Then fight for
your right to tomorrow.
Fight...
so that your name
is whistled down the ages
as a name for goodness,
for worth,
and for light.
I'm-- I'm sorry.
I-I didn't mean to.
If you take me, I'm yours.
I'll think about it,
My Lord.
I know that look
on a man's face.
Amazing what
a good night's sleep can do.
More like a night
not sleeping.
There's your army, My Lord.
You do your men
and Jomsberg proud.
This will be a great battle.
They'll sing songs about
the few that went to Trondheim
and smashed
the armies of the god.
Men, we leave soon,
before Beothric finds out!
Forgive us, sire.
We have traitors in our midst.
Some of our brothers have
sided with your brother, sire.
The king is dead.
The druid.
What are they to do
with only a few hundred men?
They are the Jomsberg.
Who knows what they'll do?
I care little.
Tomorrow I shall have
the horn,
and no army
in this middle kingdom
will be able to stop me.
The Gates of Valhalla, Mittgard
and Helheim will swing wide.
My Lord, what is this plan?
What are you saying?
I shall open the pathway...
to open the gates
of Heaven and Hell.
It will wreak havoc
upon our world.
I care little for your world.
Thousands of our people
will die.
These people fell our fields,
build our ships.
Surely you cannot be unaware of
the havoc that this will cause.
Fool! Of course I am aware.
Only by my forging mayhem
upon the world
can the Christian god
be destroyed forever.
This is not about
our Viking quests
or extending our realm.
It's about you and the gods
at the expense of mortals.
What care have I for mortals?
I am a god.
You may care little, My Lord,
but I'll not you lead us
into our own destruction!
You forgot one thing.
Only those
with the blood of gods
can use the weapons
of the gods.
You, Wolfred...
suffer from a lack of vision.
Kings of the North,
prepare your men.
The battle for the middle
kingdom starts at sunrise.
Captain.
I name you King of Nordland,
in place of Wolfred.
[pants]
So many.
Your men probe the shield wall
right to left
and throw our full weight
on the left flank
once the wall has broke.
- And if we break it?
- Then we push through.
And if Thor shows up
before then?
I'll shall call him out,
and we'll fight to the death.
The eclipse.
It will begin soon.
Men, we camp here
for the night.
Men of Jomsberg,
Vikings, brothers...
across the ridge
is the army of the north,
more than a thousand strong.
We are but a few.
Five to one.
If you wish,
I'll ride to their captains
and ask for an extra day
so they can gather more men.
It only seems fair.
Some of you know me.
Some of you have bled with me.
Some of you have heard
tall tales of battles won,
of gods and goddesses.
This is me,
Eirick of Jomsberg,
and my song is
not yet finished.
The measure of a man is not
measured in his battles won,
the dead by his swords,
or the gold he has stored away.
A man is measured
by his courage,
his devotion to family,
his willingness
to grab his destiny.
If we do not fight this day,
there will be
a generation of terror,
and the gods will unleash
horrors of the old age.
Today you do not
fight for yourself.
Today...
you fight for your wives,
your sons, your daughters.
If you should die this day,
die with the faith that you
have stood shield to shield
with your brothers.
And die as a Viking should,
with honor.
Come.
Follow me!
[cheering]
Now that's more like it.
[man shouting commands]
They don't stand a chance
against our mighty army.
Take position!
To the wall!
[rumbling]
[shouting]
Fire!
Take cover!
First wave, form a new line!
Retreat!
Come on, you bastards!
Come on!
We've broken down the wall,
Captain,
but we've lost many of our men.
We have to win this.
We'll fight to the very end.
[shouting]
Another captain comes!
My Lord, your brother is dead.
We pledge ourselves to you
in your noble cause.
Come, let us join the fight.
- Sire.
- Speak, man.
They've broken to the left.
They've reinforced.
Let's ride.
Gregor!
- We're broken.
- Who will tell Thor?
To hell with him.
I ride to my ships and beyond.
Stay if you wish.
- Save yourself if you can.
- You're not Vikings.
To hell with you, too,
King of Nordland.
Back to the fortress!
Retreat! Retreat!
- There's none left for us.
- Fine with me.
I didn't come here
to be a casual observer.
I won't let you do it.
So...
what now, Eirick?
You cannot stop me.
Did you come just to see me
open the Gates of Helheim?
I may not have the horn,
but do you see me running?
I've come to face you, Thor,
and die if I must.
Ah, yes.
The horn.
By blowing this here,
you thought to send me
back to Valhalla.
I will try.
You cannot stand against me,
my son.
[thunderclap]
Your father did not know
the truth.
He took after his form
to lay with your mother.
I did not need such artifices.
She was a willing whore
to my desires.
Did you truly believe
a mortal man could
rise from the dead,
could drink from a cup
of Frey without dying?
Could lay with
the Goddess of Love
without being driven insane
by desire?
The blood of the gods
is in your veins.
My blood is in your veins.
Yield to me
and together we shall rule
the world with our fist,
and we shall drive
the one god and his son
from the face of the earth.
I will not let you destroy
the middle kingdom.
Then fight.
[whips crack]
No! Eirick!
Your weapon
holds no fear for me!
I have the blood
of the gods in me.
I have the blood of the gods.
[horn blows]
May I have
the Horn of Helheim?
Lord Frey.
Poor Thane of Jomsberg.
You can blow this
until the sea freeze is over,
but it was never meant
to blow Thor away.
No, it was meant
for another...
higher purpose.
- But you said--
- Yes.
I told you only an undead
could enter Hell.
Being gods,
both Thor and I needed you
to obtain this horn.
You see,
three relics are needed
to open the gates of Heaven,
Earth and Hell.
The necklace of Mary Magdalene
from Mittgard,
the Hammer of Thor
from Valhalla,
and the Gilded Horn
of Helheim.
You poor fool.
The horn is the final key,
and you've brought it to us.
Why are you doing this?
Men... are ungrateful.
We have protected you for ages,
then you abandon us
for some new god?
It is time for man
to pay the price.
My son...
together we could have
ruled the world.
[screaming]
FREY: The horn's breaking!
Something's wrong.
Why is this happening?
Because it's a fake!
I gave a false horn
to Beothric!
I listened to what
the earth told me!
ALCUIN: I knew your plans, Frey.
And I learned
you would betray us.
Nature will always tell
the story of a traitor.
No one--
god or mortal--
should rule the earth!
[screaming]
Brynna.
It's a good death.
It should've been me.
No one chooses their fate.
You're not responsible
for my life
or anyone else's.
Only your own.
[groans]
I'm at peace.
I have a glorious death.
Send me back to sea.
Behold, Brynna the Fair.
You see your mother
awaiting you in paradise?
Behold, Gregor the Formidable.
Do you see our kinsmen?
Behold, Warick the Wise.
Do you see your rest
awaiting you in paradise?
Behold, Bernard the Viking.
His paradise is his honor
and family.
And there I see my friends
surrounded by those
who have gone before.
For when my time comes,
I shall join them there gladly.
ERICK: Such marks the passing
of the old gods
from middle kingdom.
Mankind is now free
to choose their gods,
their friends,
their enemies.
I became known as
Eirick Thorson.
My men and I have become the
guardians of the holy relics.
Not many know of our existence,
so our song...
our song is not yet sung.
♪ [rock]
♪ [continues]